♪♪（三味線）
木ノ葉の皆々様。
People of the Leaf Village.
歌と踊りで　しばしの憩いを
お届けにまいりまして　ござ～い。
I am here to offer you a moment's respite
with some song and dance.
♪♪（三味線）
《ハナレ…》
Hanare...
ano suiheisen ga touzakatte iku
Far beyond the horizon it continues
ao sugita sora ni wa ashita sura egake nakute
A sky so blue, you can't draw tomorrow
iki mo dekinai kurai yodonda hito no mure
It's stifling with crowds of people down here
boku wa itsukara koko ni moguri kondan da?
Just when did I dive into this?
kanashimi nante hakidashite mae dake mi tereba iin dakke?
Spit out sadness and keep looking ahead, right?
sore ja totemo matomo de irarenai
You can't stay true to yourself like that
subete o boku ga teki ni mawashite mo
Even if I turn against everything,
hikari o kasuka ni kanji terun da
I still feel glimmers of light
soko made yuke sou nara
If I could only reach it...
iki o shitakute koko wa kurushikute
I want to breathe, I'm suffocating here
yami o miageru dake no boku ja
Only looking up into the dark means,
ukabu houhou mo nai daibaa
I'm a diver who can't surface
iki o shite mite
Take a deep breath
tada no shiawase ni kizuitara mou nidoto oborenai yo
Discover joy, plain and simple and you'll never drown
- Leaf's History -
Kakashi Love Song
((よっ　任務ご苦労さん。
Hey. Good job on
another mission.
（ナルト）いやぁ～
やっと夢にまで見た→
Now I can finally
eat Ichiraku ramen!
一楽のラーメンが食えるってばよ。
（サクラ）悪くないわね
ナルト　アンタのおごりよ。
Sounds good.
You're treating, Naruto.
えぇ！？　いいけどね　いいけどさ
っていうか→
Huh? Oh, fine already.
But you know...
サスケ！　たまには
お前が　おごれって！
How about you treating us
for a change, Sasuke?
（サスケ）フン！　俺は　今すぐ修業だ。
I'm off to train.
じゃ　カカシ先生が…。
Then, maybe Kakashi Sensei can...
あん？
Huh?
へぇ～。
Wow...
きれいな人。
She's beautiful.
捕縛されたのか。
Was she arrested?
（コテツ）なんでも　女芸人に扮して→
I'm told she's a kunoichi who
disguised herself as a street performer
火の国の情勢を探っていた
くノ一らしいですよ。
to gather information
about the Land of Fire.
これから　どうなるんだ？
あの人ってば。
What's going to happen
to her now?
（カカシ）そうだな　どれほどの
情報を得たか尋問されるだろう。
Well, she'll be interrogated to
see just what she found out.
ありとあらゆる手が使われる。
彼女が口を割るまではね。
They'll use whatever
means necessary.
Until she starts talking.
（イビキ）ようこそ　正直者の部屋に。
Welcome.
To the "Honesty Room."
ほお　お前の尋問に
口を割らぬとは→
She is well trained to be able to
resist your interrogation.
相当の手練れだな。
うめき声もあげません。
Not even a single moan, sir.
聞こえてくるのは
歯ぎしりだけです。
Only the sound of
her gritting her teeth.
ハハハハ！　見あげたくノ一よの。
What an impressive kunoichi.
ならば　沈黙のなかに
声なき声を探ることじゃ。
Well then... We'll have to reach into
that silence and find her inner voice.
（イビキ）わかりました。
I understand.
あの人を呼んでください。
Then please summon Inoichi.
《ハナレ：雲みたい…。
They look... like clouds.
あの日の雲のよう…》
Just like the ones
from that day.
(ムチは　やめだ。　アメをくれてやる))
We're done with the pain.
Time for a more
humane approach.
((ハナレよ…
火の国に密かに潜入し→
Hanare...
Infiltrate the Land of Fire and investigate
the state of affairs in the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉の情勢を探ってまいるのだ。
（ハナレ）あの　木ノ葉の里ですか…。
The Hidden Leaf Village?
我が国が
今日まで生き延びたるは→
Our nation has survived through the years
not with military might, but espionage.
軍事よりも
諜報に重きを置いたがため。
情報を得ることにより
先手を打つことができ→
We use the information we gather to
plan strategies and gain the advantage
国家間の外交　紛争危機を
有利に運んできた。
in diplomatic negotiations with
other nations to avert conflict.
我が国の命運は→
The fate of our nation rests
in your hands, Hanare.
ハナレ…　お前たちの働きに
かかっておるのだぞ。
(（ハナレ）はっ！　必ずや))
Yes sir!
I will not fail you.
((あれは…
この額当ては→
What's that?
That headband...
鍵の国　錠前の里…。
It belongs to the Hidden Lock Village
in the Land of Key.
捕まったのは
木ノ葉に潜入する前。
She was captured before
she had infiltrated the Hidden Leaf.
さしたる情報は
得ていないようだな。
She didn't learn anything
of importance.
《悪いが…　今度は　こちらが
お前の里の情報をもらう》
Sorry, but now it's my turn to get
some information about your village.
《どういうことだ？
What's going on?
里らしき記憶を
まったく持っていない》
She has no memories
about her village at all.
気のせいか。
Was it my imagination?
《ん？》
えっ？
What?
俺のガキの頃の記憶を？
あぁ。
Memories of me as a kid?
Yeah, do you remember anything?
お前　覚えてないか？
えぇ。　会ったこともないですね。
No, I've never met her.
そうか…。
I see.
他にわかったことは
ありませんか？
Did you learn anything else?
たいしたものはない。
Nothing significant.
肝心の錠前の里の記憶は
一切なかった。
And she had no memory
regarding the Lock Village.
おそらくは　消去したんだろう。
She probably purged it.
消去…。
Purged?
だが　妙に引っかかるんだ　何かが。
But, something is bothering me.
Just something...
お前の記憶を
持っていたこともそうだが→
Part of it is the fact that
she had memories of you.
アイツは　何かを隠している。
But she's hiding something.
俺でも見つけ出せない何かを。
Something that even I can't dig up.
それを　カカシ
お前に見つけ出してほしいんだ。
And that, Kakashi, is what
I want you to find out.
えっ　俺がですか？
Huh? Me?
俺は　情報部じゃありませんよ。
But I'm not a member of
the Intel Division.
お前の写輪眼なら→
With your Sharingan,
アイツの心の中を見通すことが
できるかもしれない。
you may be able to see
further into her psyche.
お前は　バカなのか？
Are you a fool?
諜報のために
潜入した私に　里の中を。
You're showing me around the very village
I infiltrated for espionage.
どこも変わりゃしないよ
里の様子なんて。
You won't find anything different here
than in any other village.
それにあんな所にいたら
息苦しいだろ？
And besides, I thought you could use
some air after being in that stuffy place.
う～ん　どの花がいいかな？
Which flower should I choose?
ん？　何？
What?
Uh-huh...
えっ　ウソ！
What? No way!
ええ！？
What?!
カカシ先生が？
Kakashi Sensei?!
カカシ…。
Kakashi?
やっぱ　お前も気になるか？
Are you curious too?
俺は　別に　そんな…。
It's not like that.
あの人！
ほら　この前　門で見た→
It's that lady!
You know,
the one we saw at the gate.
スパイだって言ってた。
あっ　あのきれいな人だってばよ！
The one accused of being a spy.
Oh yeah! That pretty lady!
カカシが　なんでそんなヤツと？
What's Kakashi doing with
someone like her?
あっ　おい！
Hey!
来いよ。
Come over here.
別に　アンタから何かを
聞き出そうってわけじゃない。
It's not like I'm trying to
draw out information from you.
１日　一緒にいてくれって
頼まれただけだから。
I was just asked to spend
the day with you.
今日が終われば　お役御免だ。
Once the day is done,
so is my duty.
私はどうなる？
さぁな。
What will happen to me?
Who knows?
あの雲　ナルトに似てるな。
That cloud resembles Naruto.
その横は　サスケか？
And next to that is...
Sasuke maybe?
私には
私を産んでくれた母や父に見える。
I see... my mother and father,
who gave me life.
会ったことはないけど。
Although I never met them.
辛いとき　悲しいとき
いつも私は雲を見上げていた。
When things got hard, when I was sad,
I always looked up at the clouds.
雲をじっと見て
その形から空想した。
I'd stare at the clouds
and imagine.
里の様子を…
里にいるはずの両親を。
Life in the village...
And my parents who
supposedly live there.
でなければ耐えられなかった。
Otherwise,
I couldn't have endured.
両親も知らず　里も知らず→
Not knowing who my parents were,
and not knowing about my village.
諜報のために生まれた私の宿命に。
Or my fate of being born simply
to become a spy.
よく　聞こえねえなぁ。
I can't hear them.
でも　なんかあの２人
いい感じじゃない。
But they seem suited
for each other.
フン　くだらん。
もっと近づくってばよ。
How silly.
I'm going to get closer.
私は里を知らない。
I don't know my village.
万が一　捕まったとき
里の情報がもれないように→
I was raised outside the village,
so that I couldn't divulge any information
in case I was captured.
里から離れ育てられた。
今まで
見たこともない故郷のため→
And to this day, I risked my life
to carry out missions
命を削り　任務を遂行してきた。
for a homeland
I've never even seen.
だから　必要だった　故郷が。
That's why it meant everything...
私を褒めてくれる人々が。
To have a home.
To have people who would accept me.
何で　俺に話す？
Why tell me?
沈黙をとおしてきた　アンタが。
You've remained silent
all this time.
それはあなたが教えてくれたから。
That's because...
you taught me.
ん？
あなたを見て　すぐにわかった。
I knew the moment I saw you.
あのときの少年だと。
That you were the boy
from back then.
（ハナレ）母と父に会いたくて
里へ向かった。
I wanted to see my parents
and I set out for the village.
でも　道に迷って
どうすることもできなくて。
But I got lost and
was feeling helpless.
あなたは言った。
You told me to look up at the clouds
whenever I'm feeling lonely.
「悲しいときは雲を見上げろ」って。
「雲は　自分が望むものに
形を変え見せてくれる。
Because clouds change their form
so you can envision the things you wish for.
心に希望がある限り
雲は応えてくれる」って。
You said as long as you have hope,
the clouds will always answer your call.
いつも　あの雲に
あなたの面影を探していた。
I always searched for
your likeness in the clouds.
だいぶ　違っちゃったけど
あなたを見て　すぐにわかった。
So I recognized you immediately,
even though you've changed quite a bit.
私の心には
いつもあなたがいたから。
Because you've always
been in my heart.
あなたは　私の希望だった。
You were my hope.
お～っ
何か　盛り上がってるってばよ。
Whoa... Things are
starting to heat up.
あっ　バ　バカ　ナルト！
Wait, Naruto! You'll...
（２人）あ～っ！
コラ　お前たち！
Hey, you three!
貸して　貸して…。
Huh?! Uh...
You see, this is...
お　おめ　おめ
おめでとうだってばよ！
Give me that!
C-Congratulations!
はぁ？
Huh?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
錠前の里に
我が里の上忍　リイチが捕獲された。
The Lock Village has captured Riichi,
one of our jonin.
錠前の里？
The Lock Village?
あの　ハナレとかいう　くノ一の…。
You mean the village where
that kunoichi is from?
うむ。　それで　向こうから
リイチとハナレの交換を申し出てきた。
Yes...
And the other side has proposed
to exchange Riichi for Hanare.
まぁ　幸い　ハナレは
火の国や　木ノ葉の情報を→
Fortunately, it seems Hanare
holds very little information
ほとんど持たぬというではないか。
ならば　向こうに返しても…。
about the Land of Fire and
the Leaf Village.
So releasing her
would be harmless.
いや　ダメです！
彼女を…　ハナレを返すのは反対です。
No, you can't!
I'm opposed to returning
Hanare to them!
ん？
変化の可能性は　ゼロ。　リイチです。
間違いありません。
It's not a Transformation Jutsu.
That is definitely Riichi.
では　互いの陣営から
１名だけが付き添い→
All right! One man from each side
will accompany their prisoner,
おのおのの捕虜を
橋の中央で交換する。
and the exchange will be made
at the center of the bridge.
よろしいか？
（カカシ）了解した！
Agreed?
Agreed!
カカシ先生。
こんなことになるなんて…。
Kakashi Sensei...
I never thought it would
turn out like this.
行かせない！
I won't let you go.
ハナレ！
必ずや　木ノ葉の情報を持ち帰れ。
Hanare!
Bring back information on
the Hidden Leaf without fail!
逃げい！
Retreat!
始まったってばよ！
It's begun!
おっちゃん　降伏するってばよ。
Old man, give up!
錠前の忍を　なめるでない。
Don't underestimate us Lock ninja.
いったん　閉じた鍵は
死んでも開かぬ！
Once a key is locked,
not even death could open it!
どうして　わかった？
How did you know?
あのときだ。
That day...
アンタは　あのとき
瞳で　印を結んでいた。
You were weaving a sign with your eye.
無意識に　俺は　写輪眼で
アンタの印を先読みし　術を知った。
Without realizing it, my Sharingan read
ahead of your sign and I learned your jutsu.
その術で俺は俺自身の脳内を見た。
With that jutsu, I was able to
see inside my own brain.
アンタの右目は
外の世界を見る目じゃない。
Your right eye does not look
at the outside world.
アンタの内なる世界…　脳内を→
That eye sees your inner world,
inside your own brain
そして　脳内に入ってきた
侵入者の心の内を見る目だ。
and it can look deep into the thoughts
of anyone who infiltrates your mind.
アンタは　わざと捕まり
脳内に　尋問者をおびき寄せた。
You purposely let yourself be captured
and lured your interrogator into your brain.
そして　その陰で
尋問者の脳内から情報を得ていた。
And you were secretly
gathering information
from the interrogator's mind
without him knowing it.
いのいちさんの
木ノ葉の里に関するすべてを…。
Every bit of knowledge that Inoichi
had about the Leaf Village.
そして　捕虜交換によって
情報を　木ノ葉から持ち出す。
And you would take the information
with you during the prisoner exchange.
最初　捕虜交換に反対だったが
リイチさんは助け出したい。
At first,
I was opposed to the swap.
But I wanted to rescue Riichi.
そこで　捕虜交換した直後に→
So we planned to recapture you
immediately after the prisoner exchange.
再び　アンタを捕獲しよう
という作戦を立てたのさ。
必要ないわ。
盗んだ情報は　脳内で削除した。
That wasn't necessary.
The information I stole...
has already been deleted from my brain.
その言葉を信じろと？
You expect me to believe you?
あなたの　その目で
確かめたらいい。
See for yourself with that eye.
私が　そう望んでいるから→
It's what I wish,
so I know you will believe me.
あなたは　きっと
信じてくれている。
ハナレ…。
木ノ葉は　私が
ずっと思い浮かべていた→
Hanare...
The Leaf Village was just like what I had
imagined of the home I have yet to see.
まだ見ぬ故郷と似ていた。
あなたと里を歩いて→
初めてなのに
ずっと懐かしかった。
As I walked with you
through the village,
I felt so at home, even though
it was my first time there.
ナルト君たちから祝福されて→
When Naruto and his friends
gave us their blessing,
私は　この里に迎えられたって
本気で思った。
I felt like I was accepted
in to the village.
だから　私は…
私の故郷を裏切れない。
I truly believed so.
And... that's why I can't
betray my home.
お前…。
このまま　味方のもとに帰っても→
You...
Even if I go back now,
情報を消去した私は
とがめられ　処刑されるでしょう。
I'll probably be charged for erasing
the information I had, and be executed.
だったら　あなたの手にかかって
死ぬほうを選びたい。
If that is the case, then I choose
to die at your hands!
生まれて初めて　故郷の…
私の　ふるさとのために→
I'll be able to die believing,
for the first time in my life,
何かをすることができたって…。
I was able to do something good
for my home. For my birthplace...
そう思って死ねる。
忍のプライドを
なくした者は　斬れない。
I cannot kill someone who
has lost her pride as a ninja.
忍なら　一時の感情に流されず
最後まで任務を遂行するべきだ。
A ninja never allows their emotions
to get in the way of the mission.
俺は　そういうアンタと
最後まで戦いたかったよ。
I wanted to fight you as
a ninja until the end.
それが…　あなたの答えなの？
So that's your answer.
行け。
Go.
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
（サクラ）ハナレさんは？
Where's Hanare?
ああ…　追い詰められて
諦めたのか　崖から飛びおりた。
I guess she felt cornered
and gave up.
あっぱれな忍だ。
She jumped off the cliff.
そんな…。
An admirable ninja.
これで…
よかったのかよ？　カカシ先生。
- No...
- Are you okay with this, Kakashi Sensei?!
もし　あの姉ちゃんが
本当に　カカシ先生のこと→
What if that lady
really did love you?
好きだったとしたら…。
やめろ。　くだらない。
Enough!
It's pointless.
shiranai wo riyuu ni nigete bakari de
Always using "I don't care" as an excuse to run away
rakuna michi wo susumu no wakantan da yo ne
It's simpler to follow the easy path, isn't it?
demo ima dakedo kono isshu wa
But this moment right now
dare no mono demo naiyo
Belongs to no one
what's going on, what's going on
chiisai koroni egai teta
In order to become the person
nari tai jibun ni naru tameni
I wanted to be when I was little
nani shite nani wo mirebaii notte
What should I do? What should I see?
mayocchi yau toki mo aru yo ne dakedo
Sometimes I'm confused, but...
(anytime) kitto ima daijina mono
(Anytime) What's really important now
(anytime) sore ha koko ni aru kara
(Anytime) ...is right here with us
(anytime) kowagaranai de sono mama
(Anytime) So don't be afraid
ikou shinjite
And just go, Believe
shiranai wo riyuu ni nigete bakari de
Always using "I don't care" as an excuse to run away
rakuna michi wo susumu no wakantan da yo ne
It's simpler to follow the easy path, isn't it?
demo ima dakedo kono isshu wa
But this moment right now
dare no mono demo naiyo
Belongs to no one
what's going on, what's going on
hey, hey, hey I think u can do it !
yoku mimi wo sumasete kimi wo yobu hou e
Listen closely and follow the voice that's calling you
hiru no aida no aida made sagashi temite yo
Look carefully between the buildings
mitsukaru yo kitto
I'm sure you'll find it
jibun wo ugokasu nanika
The thing that moves you
（くもじい）もしもし？
そこのあなた。
Next Episode
たまには　空から日本を
眺めてみるというのは→
Hey, Neji! Can you help us out
with our interview?
どうじゃろう？
We want to make a newspaper
about Naruto's achievements!
今回は
今年　最後の放送ということで→
Sorry, but ask someone else.
That's mean of you, Neji.
これまでに飛んだ
さまざまな場所から→
All the younger students are
looking forward to this!
こりは！　という不思議なものを
表彰しながら見ていくぞ。
Please!
Oh, fine. Then let me tell you
a very special story.
題して　「空から日本を見てみよう
なんじゃこりは？大賞２０１０」！
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Neji Chronicles"
Neji Chronicles
Now listen very carefully...